Chong Han Chua

fifthrevision.com johncch@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/johncch San Francisco, CA

Hello

Product leader with 15+ years exp designing technical products and scaling teams. Expertise in translating complexity into intuitive experiences, driving 0-to-1 product strategy, and delivering measurable impact. I'm focused on designing trustworthy AI that amplifies human judgment, creativity, and effort.

Experience

Fractional Head of Product & Design Self-employed, Mar 2024-Present

- Orchestrated 0-to-1 product strategy for AI startups Butter Labs (fintech) and Dryft (smart manufacturing) that acquired key customers and unlocked \$3M+ in oversubscribed seed funding.
- Crafted <u>Chorus</u>'s artist-centric design language that won marquee music-club partnerships (Modest Mouse, The Black Crowes, etc.) and crossed revenue milestones.

VP of Design CodeSee (exited to GitKraken), Mar 2022-Feb 2024

- Partnered with co-founders on product strategy through customer discovery resulting in >\$1M in pipeline.
- Shipped <u>Service Maps</u>, <u>Function Maps</u> and Automations, creating novel approaches to code visualization that improved developer productivity.
- Designed CodeSee AI, an agent-powered canvas for visualizing and querying codebases.

Head of Digital Experience Advanced MedTech, May 2019–Feb 2021

- Reported directly to the CEO as one of 15 senior leaders in a 1,500-person company. Built and led a 6+ person digital team across PM, design, and marketing.
- Launched new digital business in Urology delivering apps in partnership with Pyx Health and Lit-Control.
- Created Worst Pain Ever, growing it to the largest online kidney stone patient community with 300k+
 members in 6 months with 2M+ content views, establishing new KOL relationships in the US.
- Led global digital marketing transformation, created and grew cross-functional team to 10, improving traffic by 150%+, conversions by 4.5x, driving \$6M+ in pipeline.

Product Design Lead Honeycomb, Oct 2017–April 2019

- First design hire, built UX foundations that contributed to 2x ARR growth and next funding round.
- Redesigned core query workflow, significantly improving product adoption among engineering teams.
- Designed and shipped Traces, BubbleUp, and APM which are marquee product differentiators from incumbents that drive sales conversations and revenue.

Senior PM (Product & UX) Microsoft, Oct 2011–Dec 2015

- Led UX strategy for Outlook.com redesign and rebrand from Hotmail, praised by WSJ as having a "remarkably user-friendly interface" and being "a winner".
- Product managed key Outlook.com features including compose, sweep, and rules, increasing user engagement and improving competitive position against Gmail.
- Built Twist, an iOS app for photo communication, as part of Office's Snacky Apps portfolio.

Additional Experience 2008–2024

- Co-founded LayerNext (2022-2024). Computer vision (CV) infra pivoted to AI business insights.
- Led development of nSight Surgical's fundraising prototype (2021), a CV surgical tool tracking system.
- Consulted on design for Escher Reality (2017, exited to Niantic) building AR applications and interfaces.
- Co-founded Echlo (2016-2017), pioneering real-time location sharing with minimal battery consumption.
- Software Engineer at IBM (2008-2010), building retail flow software for Singapore's largest telco.

Education

Masters in Human-Computer Interaction Carnegie-Mellon University, 2011

B.Eng (Hons.) in Electrical Engineering National University of Singapore, 2008